<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>io.github.CyberTimon.RapidRAW</id>

  <name>RapidRAW</name>
  <summary>A non-destructive, and GPU-accelerated RAW image editor built with performance in mind</summary>
  <developer id="io.github.CyberTimon">
    <name>Timon Käch</name>
  </developer>

  <metadata_license>FSFAP</metadata_license>
  <project_license>AGPL-3.0-only</project_license>

  <supports>
    <control>pointing</control>
    <control>keyboard</control>
    <control>touch</control>
  </supports>

  <description>
    <p>
      RapidRAW is a modern, high-performance alternative to Adobe Lightroom®. It delivers a simple, beautiful editing experience in a lightweight package (under 20MB) for Windows, macOS, and Linux.
    </p>
    <p>
      I developed this project as a personal challenge at the age of 18. My goal was to create a high-performance tool for my own photography workflow while deepening my understanding of both React and Rust, with the support from Google Gemini.
    </p>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.CyberTimon.RapidRAW.desktop</launchable>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://github.com/CyberTimon/RapidRAW/blob/v1.3.10/.github/assets/editor.png?raw=true</image>
        <caption>Editor interface</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>
  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/CyberTimon/RapidRAW</url>

  <releases>
    <release version="v1.3.12" date="2025-09-09">
        <url type="details">https://github.com/CyberTimon/RapidRAW/releases/tag/v1.3.11</url>
        <description translate="no">
            <p>Clipping Warnings</p>
            <p>You can now toggle clipping warnings in the Curves tool to highlight overexposed areas in red and underexposed areas in blue.</p>
            <p>Update Notifier</p>
            <p>With the new update notifier, you’ll never miss an update.</p>
            <p>Other Improvements</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Updated all dependencies and migrated from Rust 2021 to Rust 2024 (thanks @RayJW).</li>
                <li>Improved performance through updated dependencies.</li>
                <li>Enhanced accuracy in the HSL panel.</li>
                <li>Fixed the inverted tint slider (you may need to readjust existing edits).</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
    </release>
    <release version="v1.3.11" date="2025-08-31">
        <url type="details">https://github.com/CyberTimon/RapidRAW/releases/tag/v1.3.11</url>
        <description translate="no">
            <p>ComfyUI Integration</p>
            <p>ComfyUI integration has been significantly improved to make it more accessible and user-friendly. You can now:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Select a custom inpainting workflow or use the built-in default workflow.</li>
                <li>Define and map which models should be loaded.</li>
                <li>See which custom nodes you need to install, in order to use the default workflow.</li>
            </ul>
            <p>RapidRAW automatically handles downscaling, mask generation, patch layer composition, and saving. These enhancements make ComfyUI integration practical for everyday use.</p>
            <p>Note: Some bugs and unfinished elements may still be present. Please report any issues you encounter. Also, if you have a better &amp; easier inpainting workflow, please share it with me as I'm not satisfied with the current one.</p>
            <p>Chromatic Aberration Correction</p>
            <p>A new tool for chromatic aberration correction has been added.</p>
            <p>Other Improvements</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Changing folders now cancels previous thumbnail generation and folder indexing jobs, preventing performance slowdowns on many machines.</li>
                <li>LUT's parser is more robust / less error prone now.</li>
                <li>Mask grow / feather parameter now correctly applies on the final image.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
    </release>
    <release version="v1.3.10" date="2025-08-24">
      <url type="details">https://github.com/CyberTimon/RapidRAW/releases/tag/v1.3.10</url>
      <description translate="no">
        <ul>
          <li>LUTs</li>
            You can now apply LUTs directly to your images, with support for .cube, .3dl, .png, .jpg, .jpeg, and .tiff files. This makes it easy to add color grading or use a LUT as a creative starting point.
          <li>Estimated File Size</li>
            Before exporting, you’ll now see an estimated file size, helping you balance image quality with file size for the best results.
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
